Guide to the Chaskin / Hecht Family Papers, 1917-1995 MS 919
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Chaskin/Hecht Family Papers
1917-1995
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Hecht, Celine Chaskin
MS 919
1.50 Linear Feet 2 boxes, 1 map-drawer
Two boxes consisting of photographs, news clippings, school materials, certificates and diploma, programs/booklets, correspondence, speeches, and invitations, document part of the lives of members of the Chaskin / Hecht family from 1917 to 1995.
Content Description
Photographs, news clippings, school materials, certificates and diploma, programs/booklets, correspondence, speeches, and invitations document part of the lives of members of the Chaskin / Hecht family from 1917-1995. Of particular interest is a booklet from a family reunion that contains a detailed family tree.
Biographical / Historical
Rebecca Kaminsky (1864-1940) married Benje Zion Yalchuk and had one child, Hessie. After Benje died, Rebecca married Samuel Chaskin and had three children: Ida, Izzy, and Abe. Hessie was adopted by Samuel and took the name Hessie Yalchuk-Chaskin.
Abe Chaskin (1997-1968) was born in Ukraine and immigrated to the United States in 1919. Abe married Mollie Shainock (1899-2002) in Houston in 1931. The couple had three children: Meyer, Sam, and Celine (1938- ). Abe and Mollie are interred at Beth Yeshurun Cemetery in Houston.
David Hecht was born in Romania in 1930, and immigrated to New York with his family at the age of 6. David served in the U.S. Marines and Air Force before settling in Houston in 1952. David met Celine Chaskin at Beldon's grocery store after being set up by a member of Celine's family. The two married in Houston in 1959. The couple have three children: Janet, Ronnie, and Jerry.
The family is very active with Congregation Beth Yeshurun.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Related Materials
The following collections contain materials for relatives of Fannie Berman and her descendants: MS 716, Pryzant Family Papers; MS 750, Berman Family Papers; MS 839, Miron / Berman Family Papers
Separated Materials
Three El Oroso yearbooks (1954, 1955, and 1956) removed and cataloged separately - LD7501 .S26 O76
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
photographs; certificates; memorabilia; programs (documents); clippings (information artifacts)
- Series I: Celine Chaskin-Hecht
  - Panoramic photo of San Jacinto HS granduating class, 1956 (Map-drawer 189, Folder 5)
  - San Jacinto High School, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B'nai B'rith Girls (BBG), 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Congregation Beth Yeshurun Confirmation and Adult Bat Mitzvah, 1954; 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - JCC Sports Award, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (wedding, Hadassah, family), ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adult pilgrimage to Israel / Adult Bat Mitzvah, 1973-03-13-1973-03-19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chaskin-Hecht 50th wedding anniversary, 2009-08-16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Janet Hecht
  - Articles, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Childhood correspondence (Camp Young Judaea, Israel pilgrimage), 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bat Mitzvah, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cyrus Adler BBG, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Jewish education at Congregation Beth Yeshurun, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Teen pilgrimage to Israel, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hecht-Mintz wedding, 1986-11-13-1987-05-28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - University of Texas graduation photos, 1983-05-21 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series III: Ronny Hecht
  - Jewish education and confirmation at Beth Yeshurun, 1965-1971
  - Bar Mitzvah, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Westbury Baseball, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Malev BBG Beau Nominee, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - University of Texas graduations (undergrad and law school), 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Wedding announcement, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series IV: Jerry Hecht
  - Education at Congregation Beth Yeshurun, 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Articles, 1976-1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bar Mitzvah, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Jack Lubel AZA Spring Induction, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Graduation photographs (undergrad and law school), 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Wedding invitation (Jerry Hecht / Arlene Bazarsky), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series V: Other Family Members
  - Articles, 1950-2019 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - MoShe Dayan Hadassah, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Panoramic photo from the Rebecca Chaskin family reunion, with label, 1980-11 (Map-drawer 189, Folder 5)
  - Mollie Chaskin 100th birthday, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Rebecca Chaskin family reunion, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Series VI: Oversize
  - Mollie Shainoch - Houston High School memory book, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Celine Chaskin confirmation certificate, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Bag with broken glass from Celine and David's wedding, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Gavel - Dayan Group Hadassah, Celine Hecht, President, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - Mini Torah, n.d. (Box 2)
  - High School group photograph, n.d. (Box 2)